税務寬免條例草案。
彙報法案委員會嘅商議工作。
現就法案委員會所關注嘅要點簡介如下。
並就法官及司法人員嘅法定退休年齡提早退休年齡。
喺會議上，委員普遍支持條例草案嘅立法建議。
法案委員會共舉行咗三次會議，並邀請公眾提交意見書。
主席，本人僅以二零一九年司法人員延展退休年齡修訂條例草案委員會主席嘅身份。
部分委員認為，將原訟法庭以下級別法官及司法人員嘅法定退休年齡一同延展至七十歲。
法案委員會認為，延展法官及司法人員嘅退休年齡及任期，只有助解決司法機構人手不足嘅部分問題。
及酌情提早退休嘅安排、酌情延長任期嘅安排，以及為順利實施條例草案嘅過渡安排等事宜進行討論。
七十歲，或有助吸引更多私人執業嘅法律界人才加入司法機構，並挽留經驗豐富嘅法官及司法人員。
及《香港終審法院條例》第四百八十四章，已就延展法官及司法人員嘅退休年齡及任期及其相關安排訂定條文。
條例草案只在修訂高等法院條例第四章、區域法院條例第三百三十六章、退休金利益司法人員條例第四百零一章。
委員促請政府當局及司法機構政務處採取其他措施，例如改善招聘法官及司法人員嘅方法，以紓緩人手短缺嘅問題。
然而，司法機構認為，將呢啲法官及司法人員嘅退休年齡設定為六十五歲，可避免窒礙較低級別嘅法官及司法人員獲晉升。
政府法案本會恢復2019年司法人員延展退休年齡修訂條例草案嘅二讀辯論。條例草案委員會主席梁美芬議員先就委員會報告向本會發言。梁美芬議員。
亦有助注入新血。
是否適合繼續受聘？
而原眾庭以下級別法官及司法人員嘅最高退休年齡，則可高達七十歲。
而法官及司法人員主要執行司法職責，只有少部分人員係執行行政職責。
嘅規定是否可行？因為該限制或會令部分法律執業者不願意加入法官行列。
司法人員可喺延展任期期間定期互相檢討有關嘅延展任期應否延續。
有委員建議探討放寬同埋廢除禁止法官離職後重投私人執業大律師或律師行列。
政府當局同埋司法機構政務處已經就法案委員會法律顧問提出嘅法律及草案事宜作出回應。
亦有委員建議，當局可考慮該等法官及司法人員喺工作量同埋工時方面享有更大嘅彈性。
司法機構政務處回覆嘅時候話：，由於上述既定嘅做法只在鞏固司法獨立同埋公眾對司法機構嘅信任，因此不同意就上述限制作任何放寬。
司法機構政務處回應時表示，法官及司法人員喺其任期或酌情延展前，均需通過健康檢查，以確定佢哋嘅健康狀況。
此外，退休法官同埋司法人員，除咗可以透過酌情延展任期安排繼續任職之外，亦可以考慮出任僅以臨時形式工作嘅站位法官同埋司法人員。
部分委員關注到喺延展任期期間嘅法官同司法人員因為健康轉差而未能履行其職責嘅情況，亦有委員指出，法官延長退休年齡可增加人手，值得支持。
法案委員會支持政府當局而就條例草案恢復二讀辯論，亦不會就條例草案提出任何修正案。法案委員會嘅工作詳情亦都已經載咗喺提交立法會嘅報告之內。
另一方面喺經過修訂之後嘅酌情延展任期安排下，終審法院、上訴法庭同埋原訟法庭法官嘅最高退休年齡，分別為七十六歲、七十五歲同埋七十五歲。
但係延長退休任期嘅期間，法官應專注審判工作，不應再負責法院嘅管理或行政職務。另有委員建議，當局設立機制，讓司法機構政務處同埋法官及。
主席。
判詞嘅。
特別係法律。
或者一啲社會科學嘅領域咧。
呢個問題就係我想提出一啲討論。
我希望咧喺司法機構嘅啊首長。
因為咧喺誒有啲嘅領域。
誒，我哋喺法律裏面咧，最重要咧，都係嗰個質量。
以下咧就係本人對條例草案嘅意見。
係會有更加豐富嘅一啲啊！
我個人嘅意見係支持延長法官年齡嘅。
我亦都需要提出延長法官嘅年齡咧，個過程咧，我哋希望唔係自動嘅。
其實年紀大啲咧，佢對於人生嘅經驗，佢對一啲案件嘅判決。
所以現時嚟講，我哋知道咧，誒，司法機構佢話要延長法官年齡，其中一個主要咧都係人手不足嘅問題。
我哋確實認為現場法官年齡真係只可以減少現在司法機構面對嘅制度嘅問題嘅好少好少部分。
所以咧，呢個所謂年齡嘅問題咧，基本上咧就啊，大家都唔係有好大嘅反對。譬如喺啊國際嘅法庭咧，有啲嘅國際嘅法官咧，都係即係啊年齡係達至八十七歲。
誒，探討嘅。
就係因為咧。
但係喺現時嘅香港咧。
如果我哋出現咗呢啲事情之後呢？
你好難咧，係阻止市民心目中會有一個疑問。
喺今年嘅年中、五月尾同埋六月咧。
就係有三位嘅法官，佢哋匿名噉樣。
分別出現咗咧一啲我哋其實係好唔想出現到嘅事情。
當然啦，剛才我讀我都有講過啦，能力同埋健康，我相信佢哋自己本人都會考慮嘅。
向一份報紙公開噉樣表達咗佢哋對於修例嘅憂慮，亦都明顯嘅訊息係反對呢個修例。
我諗咧就嗯喺現時嚟講咧，點解話嗰個公信力同埋中立性會係受到近期香港社會嘅關注咧？
係應該要考慮到佢要延長嘅每一位法官嘅年齡嘅候選人，或者嗰位法官本身有有品格，佢嗰個公信力，佢嗰個一直以嚟嗰個嘅表現。
亦都有一位法官咧，佢係真名實姓噉樣咧，參與咗一啲公開嘅聯署。後尾大家對翻個名咧，就發現咧佢係同現任某一位法官同名同姓。最後咧，亦都係確實咗佢係現任，仍然都係法官。
個疑問就係：咁呢啲嘅法官，當佢如果審訊一啲案件，嗰啲案件佢係同佢政見唔同嘅，特別係支持高調支持修例嘅人士嘅案件嘅時候，佢是否可以保持中立咧？
咩政見嘅人？
都係有公信力嘅。
定係高級嘅法官咧？
嗰個調查嘅過程係好艱難嘅。
但係嗰啲匿名嘅法官點算咧？
咁點樣查咧？咁噉我哋其實都可以係盡力嘅。
我諗一個匿名嘅法官咧，已經夠大家擔憂啦。
咁嗰啲延長年齡裏邊，會唔會又有呢幾位匿名嘅法官喺度呢？
仲要有三個，咁究竟佢哋係低級嘅法官啦。
我哋明白嘅，主席要調查匿名嘅人士。
咁力明點樣去處理嗰個審查咧？我哋喺個委員會係有作出要求。
有人去涉物咧，我哋就會係所有嘅成員都會簽翻一份咧法定嘅確認書。
就係我哋有時一啲委員會喺P.M.P嘅委員會嚇，權力及特權條例委員會，或者甚至我哋有啲專責委員會。
啲誒個別嘅雙方當事人律師要求，譬如法官可能要迴避嘅嚇，有親屬關係或者有利益衝突嘅問題。
公信力同埋中立性咧，真係非常之重要。所以我想就住幾個問題，第一就係喺現場法官年齡嘅程序上，會唔會亦都可以向公眾表現到，唔係話隨便自動嘅？
而係都係有一個過程嘅，呢個係第一。第二，亦都會就住成個體制點解會係今日人手咁不足，而引致好多嘅市民都認為，即係喺法院嘅審訊實在太長，長到係唔符合社會嘅期望喺呢一度咧，作一啲嘅。
我本人對於嗰位真明實性簽署嘅法官，雖然我認為都係唔恰當，但係我反為覺得佢係有承擔，因為佢係真明實性噉樣做。到時候大家可以話要求佢咧，就係迴避嗰個案件，律師亦都可以做，咁法庭亦都經常有啲。
如果唔做？
我哋知道呢。
我哋讀法律嘅人都好清楚。
但係佢係唔應該。
其實正義嘅女神。
我哋認為，起碼呢個程序都要做嘅。
Lady of Justice，佢嗰個眼係矇住嘅。
一簽咧，好多人仍然拒絕簽嘅，因為佢咧就心虛啦。
嚇！嗰個確認書就係話自己唔係嗰位匿名嘅人士。
矇住，即係話佢持任何嘅證件，其實唔會影響佢嘅。
我哋當然知道，法官都係人，佢係有權持有自己嘅一啲政治嘅睇法。
司法機構無從向公眾交代，究竟而家呢三位法官係審緊乜嘢案件呢？
去公開去表達，而表達又用匿名，但係又要話自己係法官，產生咗公眾覺得。
除咗即係真係會，我哋喺委員會提過嚇，我我哋都向其他嘅公營機構即係啊諮詢過。咁究竟一個誒啊崗位嚇特別高級嘅人嘅嘅官員？
所以當佢籤咗上去嘅時候，尤其是如果自己係法官或者法律界更加清楚，佢除咗要負上道德嘅責任，佢亦都要承受法律嘅後果。嗰個籤落去並唔係咁容易嘅，因為你係要講一個大話。
但係，即使我哋立法會或者我自己就任嘅大學，我哋都經常咧會出現，我哋真係會要調查一啲匿名嘅人士，佢可能泄露咗一啲機密，又或者喺呢個情況底下，法官係需要保持政治嘅中立性，以令到無論你。
法官係有反對修例嘅效果，而又唔需要負上法律同埋其他嘅責任。呢一個咧係我哋認為係好唔應該。而發生咗呢件事之後咧，正正就會牽涉到其他。本來大家對於退休年齡，大家係冇乜意見嘅。
主席。
因為一個社會。
言辭嘅公義就等於否定公義。
而呢啲都係急不及待，我哋需要有法庭嘅睇法。
嚇年初我聽到話thousand最少一千個嚇，而家最高係六千個。
又配合佢嗰個年齡嘅問題，咁所以呢個咧，我哋係有提出過嘅。
加上我哋佔中嘅時候，仲有成千個個案；蘇聯而家成三千幾個個案。
香港嘅法律底線係會令到嗰啲誒年青人可能唔會再犯同樣嘅事，唔會咧存僥倖之心。
我首先講講咧，我今朝先至得到最新嘅數據。現時咧係有成六千個號型申請嘅人士係排緊司法複核。
誒，我哋咧都係誒表示謝意嘅。咁因為咧，佢係好積極推動啊，司法人員嘅延長年齡。誒，我覺得咧呢一個咧，我哋亦都係誒支持。
嗱，只不過咧，我必須要提出咧，喺吸納新嘅法官，即係喺第二個point啦，喺吸納新嘅法官嗰個機制同埋個方式上咧，我就認為咧，未曾符合社會嘅需要。
尤其是牽涉到佔中、黃暴同埋騷亂呢啲咁重大嘅公共事件咧，成個社會係好期待法院係可以盡早畀一個説法，究竟香港嘅法律底線係點樣樣？
甚至立法會啊！如果退咗休嘅，佢再反聘，好似我哋喺大學都係嘅。佢可能已經係最高級嘅演講，佢反聘佢係做教授，但係佢就未必咧就會再做行政嘅工作。等佢可以專心咧喺專業嗰個發揮。
我自己咧就係都好尊重，亦都並且好欣賞咧。我哋啊，中審法院大法官咧馬道立大法官，佢就啊自己咧，亦都係啊好早嚇上誒誒早幾日就清楚噉樣講咧，佢係喺啊二零二一年，佢會喺啊。
佢嘅退休年齡嘅時候，預期退休，我諗佢可，我亦都睇得到佢嘅心跡。我相信咧，因為佢好想做成呢件事，亦都唔想帶出好似即係誒，佢係喺佢嘅任內提出呢個延長嘅年齡，係誒誒佢自己去延長。我我自己噉。
噉樣睇啫，所以佢就好清楚話誒呢個延長係佢自己咧就唔會延長啦。噉我當然係好尊重佢嘅決定，我亦都咧覺得佢係喺誒過去佢任內十幾年係對於司法嘅判決咧係真係發揮咗好重要嘅作用。咁喺呢一度咧，其實。
被告人。
first hearing。
二零一一年咧。
咁蘇聯嘅案件係咪仲要等五年十年咧？
佢亦都提出，我係有必要解釋畀公眾聽嘅。
佢曾經咧喺蘇聯之後第一個禮拜嗰個first court。
佢話remarkably係可以聽咗一千個。
我喺呢度好想講講咧，嗱英國都係普通法，並且係我哋吸收最多英國嘅經驗。
但係咧，我哋佔中嘅個案，佔中三子嘅個案，而家都仲上訴緊。
英國佢就對於處理騷亂嘅態度咧，佢係願意集中審理大量騷亂嘅案件。
佢哋咧喺一啲重大嘅公眾利益，佢直情卡梅倫係講咧，佢唔會容許啊，huge number of people arrested。
佢點樣集中審理？而佢政府亦都係法庭，亦都係有公共利益喺度咧。佢話咧，佢嘅法庭係可以。
因為對於年青嘅被告人，你要佢等三年五年都未審完，到時佢真係判罪啦，再坐多五年就係十年啦。如果你喺兩年之內你係審畢。
一個禮拜七日，二十四小時，唔係一個法庭，係好幾個法庭，係專門去審呢啲騷亂有關嘅案件，叫做disorder-related offence。
係係好耐好耐都唔審，佢要嗰啲佢亦都提及，係要嗰啲法庭應該活sit through the night as long as is necessary。
一千個，佢就加緊點解佢特別提到，因為有啲被告人咧有一個佢點咗出嚟。阿李君如，你睇呢點同呢條嘅範圍呢個非常重要啊，主席，因為我哋嘅排期佢而家嗰個吸入方式純粹透過延長年齡係無補於事，我必須要提出我哋喺委員會。
我哋應該咧要學習，真係學嘅學好，學成套。
所以英國喺呢方面好清楚嘅，佢係速審速決。
佢話咧，有個妹妹十一歲，啱啱小學畢業。
我相信香港而家最缺乏嘅咧，就係司法人員個資源。
香港的 shortage of judges means justice is often delayed.
集中我自己喺我要申報，我喺城大教咗，已經今年係第三十年。
香港大學一九六九年成立，中文大學二零零五年，我哋都廿二年。
佢哋有啲係真誠悔過嘅，阿爸爸媽媽陪埋，佢知道佢呢度直情同我哋好相似㗎。
佢哋亦都希望，如果適合嘅個案，法庭審完之後可以特別處理，譬如太細個真係無知嘅八歲、十歲、十一歲。
希望咧，法院真係落力啲去正視呢個司法人員不足嘅問題，集中給立新團主席本人僅此陳。李慧瓊議員。
President, for over decades, the problem of shortage of judges has been well known to the public at large in Hong Kong before, or at least since 1997.
佢咧就知道自己in serious trouble，好大件事要畀人拉。但係佢話：原來自己從來冇諗過咧，佢係會受法，係會被caught，會被捉嘅，要受法律嘅審判。
As was pointed out by former top official of the Department of Justice, Mr. Granfield Corz, it was said that retired judges were being recorded to fill vacancy at the judiciary. Yet, even so.
佢即刻佢坐都可能坐完啦，所以呢個咧係無分政見，唔係話邊個係成個社會，甚至嗰啲係被告嘅年輕人咧，其實都好需要你哋盡快話畀大家聽嗰啲所謂law-abiding citizens，即係話守法嘅市民，好想法庭畀一個説法。
每一年成八百幾九百個學生畢業，係qualify係lawyer。而家好多好有資格嘅刑事嘅律師，你哋係應該正式誠意去吸納佢。我真係只可以講，你哋喺吸納新血嗰度係冇主動，亦都冇吸納到令到人哋覺得係咪？
this could only be a temporary solution.
Of course, the judges require.
appointment was much much lower than the available vacancy.
would undoubtedly keep any potential candidates from coming forward to join the bench.
It was also pointed out that we may once again have to turn to overseas recruitment.
它被《南中國晨報》描述，雖然薪金和服務條件，的高級司法。
The judiciary administrator recently reported there were ten judicial vacancy in the court of first instance.
on top of which, a significant number of the existing judges will reach the statutory retirement age of sixty-five within the next five years.
It must be also seen to be done with the independent judges on the bench, for which most of the Hong Kong people should be grateful.
since 1997, the judiciary has been faithfully upholding the rule of law, ensuring that not only justice is to be done.
薪金， not a very attractive concern， coupled with the lower retirement age， and the barring from returning to private practice。
一二零一零年，二零一
Many court of first instance judges have traditionally come from the district court or the legal profession, whereas newly appointed district judges may currently lack the experience necessary for promotion.
must always be those of the right quality. It was once reiterated by Chief Justice Geoffrey Ma that it is better to leave positions vacant than to have appointment of persons not of the required standard.
In about March 2015, it was announced that out of 200 judicial posts, only 169 were filled substantially, and there have been persistent recruitment difficulty at the high court level.
司法機構真係係想我哋去幫手咧，又或者你會唔會誕生一啲集中咗喺譬如呢兩年你增加人手處理嗰啲號型申請嘅，同埋呢一啲蘇聯相關嘅佔中相關，我而家恐怕你五年十年都未審完，成個社會係好慘。因此，主席，我希望。
It was reported by the South China Morning Post at about the end of 2015 that in the three consecutive recruitment exercise for the Court of First Instance held in 2012, 2013, 2014, not all vacancies were filled. The number of candidates suitable for
7天，而家係120天。
unlikely to change, at least not within a foreseeable future.
which are not ungenerous by international standards.
to combat its shortfall, the judiciary is calling retired judges coming.
to recruit overseas judges， a practice which was common before 1997.
是 certainly well worth the serious consideration by Hong Kong, which is running the same system.
while there may be a reluctance on the part of judiciary due to the trend of localization.
this option may have to be reconsidered if the present condition of the shortage of judges remain or deteriorate.
and the shortage of court of first instance judges presumably places existing judges under even greater pressure.
It is surprising, for example, that the chief justice is paid less than the three secretary of departments, notwithstanding his central role in the legal system.
The judicial committee has recently advised that the judiciary's increasing, increasingly heavy workload has been particularly borne by those serving in the High Court.
Are closely monitored by the judicial committee, an independent body, and various review are currently underway on judicial needs, including one on benefits and allowance. Abnormality remains.
judicial shortage will also pose threat to our court system, as one of the UK top judges earlier warned. The UK's experience, as it is being one of the leading common law legal system, is certainly well worth of.
back into temporary service, temporarily promoting district court judges and relying on senior lawyers to sit as deputy judges or recorders for several weeks and years. While this may provide short-term proliferative, it is no substitutes for substantive appointments.
The judiciary, moreover, in its annual report for two thousand and fourteen, indicated its performance targets were not always being met. It confirmed once and again that the waiting time for a criminal case, from the filing of the indictment to trial in the court of first instance, was two hundred and twenty.
Although Chinese is being increasingly used in the court cases, lower courts in particular, the Basic Law provides that English is also an official language of the judiciary. Yet the bulk of magistrate court cases are now tried in Chinese. Many court of first instance trials are still conducted in English, and this is.
The three main areas were affected by the shortage.
Third area affected are judges themselves.
Pelincourt to have a higher retirement age.
一beginning can be made with the federal court. It is not uncommon for the
outside the judi, judi, judicion is worth billion a year.
If there is reluctance to extend the retirement age of all superior court justice.
在 his first appearance before the Constitution Select Committee in his new post.
second area affected is deal process. The shortage has lead, in tandem with other factors, to inefficiency.
在最高法院、在美國和在憲法法院、在奧地利和在希臘，法官是被任命為終身的。
在以色列，的 shortage of judges that has worsened over the years has led to a serious deterioration in the operation of Israel's judicial system.
在司法系統， compelling it most prominently in the last decade or so to be innovative that is introduce procedures devoid of any legal footing.
It was advocate in Malaysia that to remain and sustain judicial reforms, it is necessary that the age of retirement for superior court judges be extend from sixty six to sixty eight or seventy.
The first area is the judicial system itself, where the shortage is the primary determinant of the delay, and what the public often prescribe as procrastination plaguing Israeli courts.
The effective operation of the courts in England and Wales was under threat due to problems of judicial recruitment, increasingly heavy workloads and deteriorating working conditions, according to the Lord Chief Justice.
The current difficulties with judicial recruitment pose a threat to the discharge of the business of the court effectively, as was pointed out by the most senior judge in England and Wales to his peers. This affects the ordinary work of the civil, family and criminal courts.
additionaly，problems of recruitment to the high court threaten to undermine the world wide reputation of the judiciary of England and Wales and reduce the attraction of London as the preeminent centre for international dispute resolution. The voluntary use of the UK court by those out
在 local courts。
who earn about.
to know away, these judges。
In the range for the Hong Kong 2017.
and then increasingly brain drain by the brain bench, as the press earlier described.
民主，the growth of cases in Hong Kong, civil or criminal, the commercial disputes, local or international, is alarming.
In calendar, the retirement age is seventy-five. In Belgium, Denmark, Israel and Netherlands, Norway and Australia, the age is seventy years. In Germany, it is sixty-eight.
It will make post-retirement assignments handed down by the executive become unattractive. This will improve independence of the judiciary and strengthen the rule of law, both of which are crucial to sustain.
By this legislation, Hong Kong judiciary will raise retirement age for judges by five years to 70, and the move will increa will include pay rise for judges to counterbalance any shortcoming.
while the recruitment, the training and engagement will inevitably take time, efforts and resources. The extension of the retirement age of judges, as proposed by the bill, does appear to be constructive and beneficial to Hong Kong.
60% less than the private practice. Senior counsel with the same experience, the pay gap was only 70, 43% about a decade ago. The judiciary has since about 2012 increased the number of recruitment exercise for court of first instance judges, but
increasingly increasing the retirement age in Hong Kong courts will bring many advantages. It will bring the present judiciary in line with the norm worldwide. It will permit continuation of a strong talent pool of experienced judges. Judicial reforms recently introduced will have time to get entrenched.
for these judges, as a sector of these judges face competition from the better-paid private sectors and retirement. Now also by this legislation, the judiciary pushed back the retirement age for judges from sixty-five to seventy, in a bid to tackle the persistent manpower shortage.
The effort may trap the talent pool of the city's prosecutors' office to attract those eyeing a career change, as they may more likely to switch over than private lawyers who could not put off by a huge pay cut. Retired judges Wu Wu Guoheng did first officially from head.
Chief Executive election, he tendered himself as a retired judges for possible further service as a Chief Executive in Hong Kong. Two weeks after the Executive Council has approved a proposal to offer judges of all ranks to pay rise plus extra allowance, it was an attempt to close the expanding.
gap between between the judges and legal practitioner, which is one of the concern for the latest in contemplating a job in the judiciary. The announcement in two thousand and sixteen revealed a bleak reality as a court of first instance judges in two thousand and fifteen earned.
他説：，他這。
this day that they had hardly have time to write judgement.
255,000 a month remain.
tend to get better by the year, and the move to the judiciary is viewed as a logical career move.
difficult to recruit, whereas those in private practice can charge client tens of million of dollar per annum. Which, well, of course, I don't think. Well, I hope.
一job aspect widely considered by many as a primary source of job satisfaction, a way to contribute to the development of the common law, or in all from all.
一 veteran barrister who preferred to remain anonymous suggests that the extended retirement age be make discretionary rather than mandatory.
fee can be lower. Until March 2016, only 162 out of 200 court posts were filled on a permanent basis.
which is seven down from a year earlier due to retirement. Another deterrent for lawyer yet people can still be very smart, energetic, healthy and capable in their late 70s.
而對方法官是65。其他 senior律師，The Press spoke to raise other concerns。for for instance，法官，especially those above court of first instance level， are so overloaded with work。
Although retired judges are entitled to pensions, those above the district court level are barred from returning to private practice after stepping down from the bench at sixty-five, whereas their counterparts in the private sector can work.
branches of the legal profession, it has come to a clear consensus and opinion that extending the retirement age of the judges is not only needed for addressing the issue of shortage of judicial manpower.
The former director of the public prosecution grand field court also noted that, while a pay cut may deter private counsel from joining the bench, the terms and conditions were actually very attractive to the Department of Justice prosecutors, who are already committed to the government.
for as long as they want. The former law society president Thomaso said he support raising the retirement age and increasing judicial salaries. Hence, the solicitor who has also been a deputy judge said he could consider joining the bench later in his career.
Former bar association president Winnie Tam also gave her support to the idea of postponing postponing retirement for judges, and she wrote a column in a Chinese language newspaper, Ming Pao, stating that for many senior counsel who decide to make the switch, it will be a point of no return.
他説，他幾乎加入高等法院，在一九九零年代，但係他説他太愛做辯護工作，當檢察官要轉行，他説會幫助司法界利用檢察官的人才庫，特別因為退休年齡是六十歲，而
請你停止發言。會議在暫停，明天九時續會。